botanical.com 2006-03-15

# Privacy & Security Policy

###  Our Privacy Policy 

One of the most pressing issues today facing the online world is a company's privacy policy. This is not revealing news for us. Since 1987 Mountain Rose Herbs has never sacrificed our customers personal information for the mere advantage of shortsighted financial gain. We have never sold, traded, or rented our mailing list or customer information. For this amount of dedication to our customer's privacy, Mountain Rose Herbs received an honorable national award in 1995 for holding such a formidable business practice. 

With regards to your online privacy a large portion of companies have adopted a very benign business practice called customer "personalization" also known as "customization". What this means is that a companies server can install itself into your computer and retrieve what is known as "cookie" files. These files exist on practically every computer system. There the companies servers are fed data involving your web surfing habits, pages most viewed, items purchased, buying frequencies, personal attributes, downloads, etc. They use this information to place strategic banner ads on your browser, offer you items they think might entice you, greet you by name when you enter their site, and store personal information within their own database to help them with marketing, mailing lists, consumer demographics, buying habits, age range, etc. 

WE DO NOT employ these methods.... and we never will.   
We only monitor our web logs, which assist us in determining possible page incompatibilities, dead links, the most useful pages, and to help us create richer content. We do not store information about YOU but rather we track information on our websites performance. This tool is SOLELY used to help us improve the content of the site......nothing more. 

Our promise to you is that we will never sell, dissect, decimate, share, or trade your information. 

We do not research your buying habits, we do not sell your buying habits, and most of all we do not transfer your online purchasing and personal information onto any other machine. Everything you have given us stays with us......period. 

For more information on this please contact Shawn Donnille/Managing Partner at shawn@mountainroseherbs.com, or the Webmaster at webmaster@mountainroseherbs.com. 

### **Our Security Policy**

When it comes to a companies security policies, especially a company's website security policy, we are far ahead of the game. 

Since 1987 we have NEVER sold or traded any of our customers information, nor have we ever jeopardized that information. 

Usually, when most of us order online, all of our personal information; most importantly our credit card information is stored on the company's website server or Internet connected server. Here it lingers and potentially sits around for eons, ripe for the opportunity of attack. It's a frightening thought knowing that there are many businesses that just store credit card and buying information on a public domain! 

Immediately after you place an online order with Mountain Rose Herbs; just one person with access to the codes, promptly prints out your order, then completely deletes it from the server…. immediately. We do not let your information sit idly on a server. No part of your personal or financial information is ever stored on any computer with an outside connection. 

When we print out your order, it is taken to our in house order-processing network, which is NOT connected to the Internet in any way, nor is it connected to any outside computer. All of our customer's information is stored securely in house. 

All hard copy orders that have been printed, processed and shipped are filed in a secure and protected environment. Then burned after a predetermined time. When you place an online order over the Internet with Mountain Rose, the connection that transmits your data is secure through SSL 128 bit encryption technology. 

The website that you buy from may not be the only security threat to be concerned about. Many companies contract third parties or outside credit card processing services. Here your financial data is sent through a rather dubious line and processed by an organization that may not have the same security ethics as the company you bought from. We DO NOT contract our credit card processing services to any outside organization. It is all done in house, by hand and, by a real person who works at Mountain Rose Herbs. 

We value your input and comments. For any concerns regarding these matters please contact us at (800) 879-3337 or e-mail Shawn Donnille at shawn@mountainroseherbs.com.
